Scott House

70 Pioneer Ave, Sanford, Maine 04073 207-651-7869 ● sehouse@umich.edu

University of Michigan '14 Bachelor of Arts in History and Political Science

A graduate from the University of Michigan, with prior experience in customer relations, organizational skills, youth and urban planning, and exceptional research skills. Has training with audio and visual equipment, lesson planning, scheduling, archive document handling, and computing and clerical duties. Since graduation, he has gained employment experience in the field of education, serving as a substitute teacher, a one-on-one student support staff, a 1st grade literacy education technician, and a K through 5 Title 1 education technician. In January 2019, he went bacl to school at the University of Maine, persuing an engineering degree.

Professional Experience

H.B. Emery School, Limington, ME *Title 1 Literacy Education Technician*

Sep. 2017-Jan. 2019

- Responsible for day-to-day implementation of federal Title 1 literacy services to lower percentile students, including beginning reading strategies, grammar mechanics, and English language services.
- Conducts daily individual and group literacy instruction of varying grade levels.
- Keeps detailed records of student work schedules, student progression, and student attendance.
- Maintains thorough catalogue and organization of entire Title 1 office and all assessed materials.

Sanford Title 1 Summer School, Sanford, ME Seasonal Title 1 Literacy and Mathematics Education Technician Jul. 2016-Present

- Assisted the main classroom teacher with day-to-day educational support for summer school students.
- Conducts daily sight word assessments, literacy groups, and assists with mathematics.
- Responsible for multiple work assignments, including recess, cafeteria, and bus duty.

Margaret Chase Smith School, Sanford, ME 1st Grade Literacy Education Technician

Sep. 2015-August. 2017

- Assist main classroom teachers with day-to-day educational support for 1st grade students.
- Primary focused on conducting small reading groups of various literacy levels, but would alter instruction based on student needs.
- Assisted in taking running records to determine literacy growth, administering spelling tests, clerical duties (such as document copying, schedule formatting, and other requested tasks) and upkeep of classroom technology.

Sanford Extended School Year, Sanford, ME One-on-One Student Support

Jul. 2015-Aug. 2015

 Worked one-on-one with a 4th grade student whom required additional supervision and educational instruction. • Focused on behavioral issues and academic effort/focus

Willard School, Sanford, ME One-on-One Student Support Apr. 2015-Jun. 2015

- Worked one-on-one with a 1st grade student whom needed additional supervision and educational instruction.
- Focused on behavioral issues and academic effort/focus

Sanford School District, Sanford, ME 2015

Nov. 2014-Aug.

Substitute Teacher

- Filled in for absent classroom teachers.
- Adhered to provided lesson plans, while also making adjustments, based on potential problems/unexpected events.

•	Fulfilled various required duties, such as morning recess duty and lunch duty.	

MSAD 60, Berwick, ME Substitute Teacher

Oct. 2014-Mar. 2015

- Filled in for absent classroom teachers.
- Adhered to provided lesson plans, while also making adjustments, based on potential problems/unexpected events.
- Fulfilled various required duties, such as morning recess duty and lunch duty.

America Reads, Ginsberg Center, Ann Arbor, MI Inner City Elementary School English Tutor/Lesson Planner Sep. 2012-May. 2014

- Handled tutoring duties of upwards of three Detroit Public School students at a time.
- Constructed personalized lesson plans to accommodate the needs of each individual student.
- Regularly accessed archival materials to contribute to student's educational goals.
- Helped students to achieve quantifiable scholastic improvements, including awards and merit-based achievements.
- Operated light vehicles, carrying co-workers to and from Detroit.

University of Michigan Student Unions, Ann Arbor, MI Event Services/Audio Visual Technician/Customer Service Sep. 2012-June 2014

- Planned and enacted the assembling of customer events.
- Implemented new time management techniques to minimize time loss between assigned work.
- Monitored and supervised co-worker training and addressed specific job concerns.
- Reorganized planned client arrangements and developed new plans to accommodate client's updated concerns
- Handled and maintained sophisticated audio visual equipment and troubleshot client concerns about said equipment.

Reben, Benjamin, and March, Portland, ME *Law Office Intern*

June 2009-Aug. 2009

- Handled new client information intake, including documenting information about potential cases and forwarding them to internal staff.
- Handled legal briefs, including document transcribing and photocopying.
- Maintained communication between the legal team and clients, including mail and electronic communications.

Education

Research Certification at Gerald R. Ford Presidential Library 2011

Dec.

Bachelors Degree in History and Political Science, University of Michigan Educational Technician III Certification, State of Maine

May 2014 Aug. 2014